Okay when you're playing golf, we've covered this just a little bit but your goal on every hole should be to get a par because that means, if it's a par four you're going to get two strokes to get around the green and then you're either going to make your chip close and make the putt, or you're going to be on the green in two, and two puts so that will be your par.
So if you hit a great second shot that might leave you a short putt to make your birdie but you always have to count on trying to get a par on every hole and that would mean that you're a pretty proficient golfer.
A bogey just means somewhere along the line you've lost a shot, whether you three putted, put a ball out of bounds, put a ball in thick rough and had to recover from it, behind a tree.
There's so many things that can go wrong, that sometimes saving a bogey is a good thing.
Then a birdie is when everything goes right for the most part and you hit a couple great shots, and you get close to the hole and make the putt.
So there's par fives, there's par fours, and there's par three's.
Par three's are usually going to be under two hundred and eighty yards, anything above that will be a par four, and anything over four hundred and sixty yards will be a par five.
Now those are the distances the pros play at but for the recreational player the distances might be not quite as long, but that's generally what it is.
If you really are interested in this topic there's some good books or other reference material you can scour and really learn what all this stuff means.
That's just a good brief overview of what par, birdie, and bogey mean.